Register to The Armin Loos Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Biographical and analytical notes, 1973-1975; Series IV
  - Biographical and program notes accompanying the tape of the 1978 performance of Loos's String quartet no. 4 by the New York String Quartet, and the published score, no date; Boelke-Bomart, Inc. and Mobart Music Publications; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 19)
    See also: Musical works by Loos; Series XVI, Sound Recordings.
  - Biographical notes, 1975 Jul 14; David, Dr. Avram [Avram David Studio]; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "On the music of Armin Loos", no date; Sarch, Kenneth; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Published book by Armin Loos., 1928; Series V
  - [Der Gold-Hypotheken-Pfandbrief der deutschen Hypothekenbanken. English & German] The first mortgage gold-bond of the German mortgage banks, 1928; Loos, Armin, 1904-1971; 1 item; 53 p. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Items relating to the Armin Loos Memorial Fund, 1972-1975; Series VI
  Arranged alphabetically by author. The fund notebook was compiled by Mrs. Elizabeth Loos.
  - "Summary of Activities for the years 1972 through 1975", 1928; Armin Loos Memorial Fund of the New Britain Symphony Society, Inc.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Annual Report 1973-1974, Connecticut Foundation For the Arts; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "A compilation of pertinent material, personal data, grant acquisitions, per formances and publicity, as a progress record to date of the Armin Loos Memorial Fund for the promulgation of the music of the late composer, Armin Loos", Loos, Elizabeth, Mrs. Armin; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 21)
    notebook.
- Lecture notes by Loos, 1963-1970; Series VII
  Armin Loos gave lectures concerning music in his home from 1963-1970. These are arranged chronologically. There is a brief lecture series description by Loos in the beginning and a miscellaneous section at the end.
  - "Information about lectures", [1966?]; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Lecture notes, 53 lectures, 1963-1970; 53 items (Box 2, Folder 23-56, Box 3, Folder 57-75)
    [holographs, in part, typescripts]
  - Miscellaneous lecture notes, no date; 9 items (Box 3, Folder 76)
- School papers, 1920-1929; Series VIII
  Arranged alphabetically by author
  - [Speech for graduation from college], 1922; Loos, Armin, 1904-1971; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 77)
    [photocopy of typescript]
  - Transcript of grades received at École Supérieure de Commerce, Neuchâtel, 1924 Sep 16-Dec 17., 1 item (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Exam, no date; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 77)
    [holograph; first pages wanting? incomplete]
  - Physics homework, 1920 Feb 27; Spies, Otto; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 77)
    5 p.
- Photographs, no date; Series IX
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Mathias Jacob Friedrich Armin Loos [Armin Loos], 2 items (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Music room in his father's Dresden house, with father's portrait in background., no date; 2 items (Box 3, Folder 78)
- Diary and travel notes, 1923-1971; Series X
  Arranged chronologically with a miscellaneous section at the end. Many of the pages include sketches for poetry and prose.
  - Loose pages and 2 notebooks which include poetry. (Box 3, Folder 79-82)
  - Miscellaneous unidentified notes, no date (Box 3, Folder 83)
- Poetry and prose, 1922-1960; Series XI
  The series is divided into three subseries which include those by Loos, by others, and those whose author in unknown. The first is arranged chronologically. Those by others are arranged alphabetically by author with a miscellaneous section at the end. The final subseries is arranged alphabetically by title with a miscellaneous section at the end.
  - By Loos, XI.A
    - Loose pages containing poetry, essays, and short stories, 1922-1960 (Box 3, Folder 83-85)
      [holographs and typescripts, many are incomplete]
  - By others, XI.B
    - Loose pages in Loos' hand (Box 3, Folder 86, Box 4, Folder 87)
      Arranged alphabetically by title, with a miscellaneous section at the end [in part, typescripts]
  - Author unknown, XI.C
    - Loose pages in author's hand, no date (Box 4, Folder 88-92)
      Arranged alphabetically by title, with a miscellaneous section at the end. Includes a sketch of a libretto to an unidentified opera [in part, typescripts]
- Miscellaneous cards, certificates, etc., 1926-1971; Series XII
  - Cards (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - business card of Armin Loos [father], no date; 1 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - National Association for American Composers and Conductors [signed], 1970-1971; 1 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Social Security [signed], no date; 1 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Social Security Health Insurance [signed], 1969; 1 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Stoom, R.K., Berlin address, no date; 1 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Certificates
    - of citizenship [signed, with photograph and seal], 1940 Apr 8; 1 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - of death [photocopies, signed with seal], 1971 Mar 25; 4 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - of registration [draft] [signed, with photograph], 1926 Oct 4; 1 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Customs statement [Dresden to New York], 1930 Jan 30; 1 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Magazine articles relating to finance [typescripts], 1930 Sep 12; 2 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - passport [German Reich] [signed, with photograph], 1926 Sep 15; 1 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Pitman's School [London], rules and regulations booklet, 1926 Dec 17; 1 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Postcard of the heraldic figure of the Loos family, no date; 1 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Property of Armin Loos, lists of music and books, [1934?]; no date; 3 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Recommendations and resumes, 1926; no date; 3 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - U.S. Works Progress Administration. Federal Music Project., [1937]; 2 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    Competition announcement
- Lists of musical works by Loos, no date; Series XIII
  - Lists of works performed and taped, no date; 3 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    Covers performances from 1938-1979 Apr 12 [photocopies]
  - Lists of completed compositions by Armin Loos, no date; 2 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - List of tapes of works, no date; 1 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Sketch of list of musical works and opus numbers, no date; 1 (Box 4, Folder 95)
- Musical works by Loos, 1918-1971; Series XIV
  Loos's works have been divided into three subseries. There is a fourth subseries which is an index to his compositions by medium. Subseries:
  A. Works are arranged chronologically.
  B. Works with no date are arranged alphabetically by title.
  C. Miscellaneous works.
  D. This subseries is an index by medium of Loos's works. The indications "A" and "B" beside an entry indicate the subseries in which the main entry is found.
  Several of the works have been microfilmed. The two rolls of film are housed in Box 4.
  Tape recordings of performances of works are indicated at the end of each entry.
  - Dated Works, XIV.A
    Arranged chronologically.
    - [Works, piano. Selections], 1918-1929; 2 (Box 5, Folder 96)
      Holographs signed, in ink. 23 p. 31 cm.
      Includes Five preludes for piano (1946), 8 p.
      Contents:
      Untitled p. 1 -- 1918
      Melodie pp. 1-4 -- 1919
      Untitled pp. 4-7 -- 1919
      Idee aus Dresden 12 p. -- no date
      Barcarolle d'Hercule Amoureux 4 p. -- 1929 Apr 17
      (For a later version see: Barcarolle d'Hercule Amoureux, 1929 Apr 17, revised, 1953.)
      Photocopy of above. Excluding the Five preludes for piano, 32 cm.
    - Vier Nachstimmungen, for piano, 1919 Dec 14; 1 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      Holograph signed, in ink. [2] p.; 34 cm.
      Incomplete. No. 1 complete, no. 2 is a sketch, nos. 3 and 4, pages wanting?
    - Drei Improvisationen über ein Quartetthema, for piano, 1919; 1 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      Holograph signed, in ink. [4] p.; 34 cm.
      No. 3 incomplete, unidentified sketch on the bottom of p. 2.
    - [Quintet, piano], 1919-1920; 5 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      Holograph in ink. Score (8 p.); 36 cm.
      Incomplete, last page wanting? Copy included.
      Sketches. [7] p. with various titles: Music for string quartette, piano; Quartette; and Sinfonische Musik für Streichquartette, Klavier.
    - [Works, orchestra. Sketches], 1922; 1 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      Holographs signed, in ink and pencil, Jan 6, Feb 24, 1922. condensed scores ([4] p., 1 leaf); 34 cm.
    - Preghiera, um Stellung für mein Wirt, for piano, 1922 Jul 24; 1 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      Holograph in pencil. [1] leaf.; 32 cm.
      Last 3 p. contain a sketch of a letter to "Miss Coyne," and various music sketches.
    - Eos, toccata for piano, 1923-1924; 6 (Box 5, Folder 98)
      Sketch in ink and pencil. 19 p.; 31 cm. Incomplete, pages 12-13 and last pages wanting?
      Holograph in ink. 27 p.; 31 cm. Excerpt from Göthe's "Prometheus" on the last page, revised, 1970.
      Photocopy of above.
      Holograph in ink and pencil. 13 p.; 34 cm. On title page: excerpt from Göthe's "Prometheus." Signed Dresden den 3 April, 1924. "Gesang an Lagen des Prometheus" on back.
      2 Sketches, in ink and pencil. [2,4] p.; 31 cm. On title page of the last sketch: "O Himmel über mir, der Reiner! Tiefer! Du Lichtabgrund." Zarathustra III.
    - Gesang am Lagen des Prometheus, for piano, 1924 Jan 13; 1 (Box 5, Folder 98)
      2 Holographs, in ink with corrections in pencil. [1] leaf; 34 cm. Words in German.
      See: Eos, 1924 Apr 3.
    - Toccata, for piano, 1924 May 3; 2 (Box 5, Folder 99)
      Holograph in ink. 15 p.; 31 cm. On last page: Abend vor dem Ball Madé, Missia.
    - [Works, piano. Selections], 1924-1930; no date; 1 (Box 5, Folder 99)
      Sketches in pencil. 26 cm.
      Kleine Toccata über A -- no date
      Préambule, foxtrot, barcarolle? -- no date
      Rondo in Erinnerung an die Festgesellschaft vom 3. Mai
      Prélude -- no date
      Toccata -- 1924
      Tombeau à George Bizet -- no date
      Toccata -- no date
      Untitled piece -- 1930
      R.M.S. Titanic. See also: Correspondence between Armin and Elizabeth Loos, 1938 Nov 22. -- no date
      III. Foxtrot -- no date
      II. Pensée (an ? Spies) -- 1924 Jan 13
      Untitled, op. 2, no. 1 -- no date
      Untitled pieces -- no date
    - [Toccata, piano, no. 3] Toccata no. 3 for piano, 4 hands, 1925 Feb 11; 2 (Box 5, Folder 100)
      Holograph in ink, title page in pencil. 35 p.; 34 cm. On title page: Genève - Neuchâtel.
      Microfilm of above, roll 1 (in Box 4)
      Holograph in pencil. 16 p.; 34 cm. On last page: Genève.
    - Musik: Die Weit über den verlorenen Groschen, for piano, 1925 Apr 1; 5 (Box 5, Folder 100)
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. [12] p.; 31 cm. On last page: Montreux.
      Holograph in pencil. [5] p.; 34 cm.
      Sketches in pencil. [6] p.; 34, 32 cm. with variation in title: (Petite) Suite: Die Weit über den verlorenen Groschen.
    - [ie. Klavier Auszug] für 2 pianos, 8 Hände, 1926; 1 (Box 5, Folder 101)
      Holograph signed, in ink and pencil. [2] p.; 34 cm. Arr. of unidentified composition.
    - Barcarolle d'Hercule Amoureux, for piano, 1929-1953; 1 (Box 5, Folder 101)
      Holograph, in pencil, New York, 1929 Apr 17, revised 1953. Unidentified sketch in pencil on back. For an earlier version see: [Works, piano. Selections], 1918-1929.
    - November Night, for piano, 4 hands, 1929 Oct 12; 1 (Box 5, Folder 101)
      Holograph in pencil. [2] p.; 33 cm.
    - Musica atonale, for orchestra, 1929; 1 (Box 5, Folder 101)
      Holograph signed, in pencil. 10 p.; 35 cm.
    - [Works, piano], 1930 Mar 11; 1 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      Holograph, in ink with corrections in pencil. 4 p.; 32 cm.
    - [Songs] To the moon, 1930 Mar 31; 1 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      Holograph, in ink with corrections in pencil. 33 cm.
      Holograph, in pencil. Piano-vocal score (3 p.); 35 cm. On back: A Dinge (II), words by Shelley.
    - [Songs] Stanzas, 1930 Apr 5; 1 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      Holograph, in ink with corrections, in pencil. [5] p.; 33 cm. Words by Byron.
      Sketch in pencil, 32 cm.
    - Feuille d'Album, for piano, 1930 Jun 16; 1 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      Holograph in pencil. [2] leaves.; 32 cm.
    - [Works, piano. Selections], 1930; 1 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      Holographs in ink with corrections in pencil. 33 cm.
      Untitled work. [12] p. Incomplete, first pages wanting? -- 1930 Nov 24
      2 Notturni. [3] p. -- 1930
      Choral O Haupt von Blut und Wunden. [4] p. -- 1930
      Sonatina. [5] p. -- 1930
    - Sonatina, 1930; 1 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      Holograph in ink with corrections in pencil. [6] p.; 33 cm. Included in notebook with [Songs], 1930.
    - Trio - Idea in search of configuration, 1930-1960; 4 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      Holograph signed, in ink. Score (36 p.); 31 cm. and parts, 32 cm.
    - Trio - Another version: Metamorphoses of an idea -- no date, 1 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      Violin part. Holograph signed, in ink. 11 p.; 32 cm. On last page: 1st version. replaced by a 2nd version called "Idea in search of configuration"
    - Trio - Another version: Ciaccona (quasi fantasia), no date; 1 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      Holograph in ink. Score (18 p.); 34 cm.
    - [Variations, piano, op. 5] Variations for piano, op. 5, 1930; 1 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      Sketch in ink and pencil. [11] p.; 32 cm.
    - [Works, piano], 1930; 1 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      Holograph in ink with corrections in pencil. 35 cm.
      I. Unidentified. [2] p. Incomplete, first pages missing?
      II. With note: Aufgesehen und gesprungen und den Becher zur Hand Holde Mädchen, süsse Reben, Tal und Berg, Deutsches Land! [3] p.
    - Elegia, for orchestra, 1931 Mar 9; 1 (Box 5, Folder 103)
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil, New York, 1931 Mar 9. Score (XXII p.); 34 cm.
    - [Quartet, strings] Preghiera I, 1931 Nov 16; 1 (Box 5, Folder 103)
      Sketches in pencil. Condensed score ([1] p.); 35 cm. On back (p. 2): Sonatina per pianoforte, op. 5, sketch in pencil.
    - [Quartet, strings] Preghiera IV, 1931 Apr 27; 1 (Box 5, Folder 103)
      Sketch in pencil condensed score. ([1] p.); 35 cm.
    - [Quartet, strings] Another version: Studien (canon duplex in unison), 1 (Box 5, Folder 103)
      Holograph in ink and pencil. 35 cm.
      Preghiera I [1] p. -- 1931 Nov 26
      Preghiera II [2] p. -- no date
      Preghiera II [1] p. -- 1932 Jul 24
      Preghiera II [1] p., 1932 Jul 20 - 1933 Feb 23
    - Fantasia, for piano, 1931-1952; 1 (Box 5, Folder 103)
      Sketch in pencil. [4] p. 32 cm.
    - [Works, piano], 1931; 1 (Box 5, Folder 103)
      Sketch in pencil. [3] p.; 32 cm.
    - [Works, piano]. Selections], 1932; 4 (Box 5, Folder 104)
      Holographs in ink and pencil. 10 p.; 32 cm.
      I. pp. 1-4 -- 1932 Apr 1
      II. pp. 4-6 -- no date
      III. pp. 6-8 -- 1932 Sep 18
      IV. pp. 9-10 -- no date
    - Ciacconna, for orchestra, 1932; 1 (Box 5, Folder 104)
      Holograph, in ink and pencil. Score (72 p.); 35 cm.
      Microfilm of above, roll 2. (in Box 4)
    - Ouverture, for orchestra, 1932; 4 (Box 5, Folder 105)
      Holograph signed, in ink and pencil. Score ([17] p.); 34 cm.
      Holograph signed, in ink and pencil. Score (49 p.); 35 cm.
      Holograph, in ink. Score (45 p.); 38 cm.
    - Preghiera für Klavier I, 3 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      Holograph in pencil. [1] p.; 35 cm. -- 1933 Apr 23
      Another version, on next page: Preghiera and thanksgiving III (Dancers)
      Holograph in pencil. [1] p. -- 1933 Apr 25
      Another version, on back?
      Holograph in pencil. [1] p. -- 1933 May 25
    - [Works, piano. Selections], 1933; 5 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      Holographs in ink with corrections in pencil. [7] p.; 34 cm.
      I. p. [1] -- 1933 Apr 30
      II. p. [2] -- 1933 Apr 23
      III. p. [3] -- 1933 May 30
      IV. pp. [4-5]. 2 copies, the 2nd should read IV?
      unnumbered pp. [6-7] -- 1933 Apr 26
    - Preghiera III, for piano, 1933 Apr 26; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      Holograph in pencil. [1] p.; 35 cm.
      Unidentified sketch in pencil on back.
    - Preghiera I, for piano, 1933 Apr 30; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      Holograph in pencil. [1] p.; 35 cm. See: Preghiera, 1931 Apr 27, for original.
    - Preghiera, for piano., 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      Holograph in pencil. [1] p.; 35 cm. -- 1933 May 4
      On back: Preghiera VII
      Holograph in pencil. [1] p. -- 1933 May 7
    - Preghiera, for piano, 1933; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      Holograph in pencil. [4] p.; 35 cm.
      p. [1] -- 1933 May 16
      pp. [l-2] -- 1933 May 17
      p. [2] -- 1933 May 30
      p. [3] -- 1933 May 31
      pp. [3-4] -- 1933 Jun 1
    - [Works, piano], 1933; 2 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      Holographs in ink with corrections in pencil. [2] p.; 34 cm.
      p. [1] -- 1933 May 21
      p. [2] -- 1933 May 23
    - Preghiera, for piano, 1933 May 24; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - Preghiera, for piano., 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      Holograph in pencil. [1] p.; 35 cm. -- 1933 Jun 4
      On back: Preghiera, for orchestra.
      Holograph in pencil. condensed score ([1] p.) -- 1933 Jun 5
    - [Pieces, piano. Sketches], 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      Holographs in pencil. [4] p.; 35 cm.
      Preghiera p. [1] -- 1933 Jun 9
      Preghierd für Bah, Bah ? p. [1] -- 1933 Jun 15
      Preghiera for my wife p. [2] -- 1933 Jun 12
      Preghiera p. [3] -- 1933 Jun 13
      Preghiera p. [3] Unidentified sketch on back. -- 1933 Jun 14
    - [Pieces, orchestra, op. 4] Two orchestra pieces, op. 4, 1933 Oct 6; no date; 2 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      Holograph signedl in ink. Score (60 p.); 34 cm.
      Microfilm of above, roll 1. (in Box 4)
      Another version: Two orchestra pieces, op. 4; arr. for 2 pianos.
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. (24 p.); 35 cm.
    - [Works, piano], 1933; 1 (Box 6, Folder 106)
      Sketch in pencil. [1] p.; 35 cm. Unidentified sketch on back.
    - [Quartet, strings, no. 1] String quartet I [1st version], 1933-[1939]; 1 (Box 6, Folder 107)
      Holograph signed, in ink, with corrections in pencil. Score (12 p.); 34 cm.
    - [Quartet, strings, no. 1] String quartet I [2nd version], no date; 1 (Box 6, Folder 107)
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. Score (12 p.); 34 cm.
    - [Quartet, strings, no. 1] String quartet I [3rd version], [1939?]; 1 (Box 6, Folder 107)
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. Score (12 p.); 34 cm. and parts. 32 cm.
    - Toccata, intermezzo, finale?, for orchestra., [1933-1934?]; 1 (Box 6, Folder 107)
      Holograph in ink. Score (78 p.); 34 cm.
      Incomplete, last pages wanting? Sketch in pencil at end.
    - Preghiera für Mein Weib, for piano, 1934 Nov 15; 1 (Box 6, Folder 108)
      Sketches in pencil. [3] p.; 32 cm.
    - Te Deum, for 2 choruses (SATB), unacc, 1934; 1 (Box 6, Folder 108)
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. Voice score (6 p.); 35 cm.
    - Prayer for my wife, [for orchestra?], 1936; 3 (Box 6, Folder 108)
      Sketches in pencil. Condensed scores? ([63 p.); 35 cm.
      I. [1] p. -- 1936 Mar 3
      II. [1] p. On back. -- 1936 Mar 11
      II. [1] p. -- 1936 Mar 11
    - Prayer for my wife, for tenor and organ?, 1936 Mar 29; 1 (Box 6, Folder 108)
      Sketch in pencil, 1938 Feb 16. [1] p.; 35 cm. Unidentified sketch in pencil on bottom of p.
    - Jesaia: XLV, 8, for 4 voices, 1936 Mar; 1 (Box 6, Folder 108)
      Sketch in pencil. [1] p.; 34 cm. Unidentified sketch in pencil on back.
    - Preghiera for my wife, [for piano?] 1936 Apr 23-24, 1 (Box 6, Folder 108)
      Holograph in pencil. [2] p.; 35 cm.
    - Preludietto, for piano, 1937 Jan; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      Sketch in pencil. pp. [l-2], Pawtucket Oct. 11, 1931, is crossed out. Sketch in pencil of Sinfonia in Si-flat, pp. [3-4]
    - Prayer for my wife, for piano, 1937 Jun 28; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      Sketches in pencil [4] p.; 32 cm.
    - Prayer for my wife and her family's happiness, for voice and piano, 1937 Jul 4; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      Sketch in pencil. Piano-vocal score (pp. 2-3); 35 cm.
    - Prayer for my wife, for piano, 1937 Jul 8; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      Sketches in pencil. [4] p.; 34 cm.
    - [Works, piano], 1937 Jul 9; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      Holograph signed, in pencil. [1] p.; 34 cm. Unidentified sketch on back.
    - Prayer for my wife, for piano, 1937 Jul 12; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      Holograph signed, in pencil. [3] p.; 35 cm. Sketch of Minuetto at end.
    - For my wife, for piano, 1937 Jul 21; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      Sketch in pencil. [2] p.; 34 cm.
    - Silence, for chorus of 6 voices, 1937 Jul 30; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      Sketch in pencil. [3] p.; 35 cm. Words by Edgar Allan Poe (1840)
    - [Pieces, orchestra] Three pieces for orchestra., 1937-1948; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      Sketch in pencil. Score (6 p.), 1937 Aug 19-1948 Jun 23; 34 cm.
    - [Works, piano], 1937 Oct 18; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - Scherzetto for my dear wife, for piano., 1937 Dec 27; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      Sketch in pencil. [1] p.; 34 cm.
    - Elegy, for chorus (SSATB), unacc, [1937?]; 4 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      Holograph signed, in ink. Voice score (4 p.); 35 cm. Words by an unknown poet. On last page: Performed in Princeton by the Westminster Choir, in pencil.
      Photocopy [of copyist?] with corrections in ink. Voice score (8 p.); 2 copies, 31 and 33 cm.
      Photocopy of above. 28 cm. See also: Series XVI, Sound Recordings.
    - [Suite, piano] Little suite, for piano. op. 10., 1937-1938; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      Sketch signed, in pencil. [4] p.; 35 cm.
      I. Dawn pp. [1-2] -- 1937
      II. M.S. Lac Leman - Juin 1926 3 A.M. pp. [3-4]
    - [Trio, piano, clarinet & violoncello], 1937; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      To my dear wife
      Sketch signed, in pencil. Score ([4] p.); 34 cm.
    - [Works, piano], 1937; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      Sketch in pencil. [1] p.; 32 cm. Unidentified sketch on back.
    - Prayer for February 11, 1938, [for piano?], 1938 Feb 11; 1 (Box 6, Folder 109)
      On back: Man song -- 1938 Feb 11
      Sketch in pencil. [2] p.
    - Psalm 120 à 5 voci (canon quintuplex), unacc, 1938 Mar 29-30; 1 (Box 6, Folder 110)
      Sketch in ink and pencil. Voice score ([4] p.); 35 cm.
    - Capriccio, for piano, 1938; 1 (Box 6, Folder 110)
      Holograph, in ink with corrections in pencil. 5 p.; 35 cm.
    - [Works, piano], 1939 Jul 25; 1 (Box 6, Folder 111)
      Sketch in pencil. [1] p.; 35 cm.
    - Procession, for orchestra, 1939; 1 (Box 6, Folder 111)
      Sketch in pencil. [21 p.; 34 cm.
    - [Quartet, strings, no. 2] String quartet no. 2, 1939; 3 (Box 6, Folder 111)
      Sketch in pencil. Score ([2] p.); 34 cm.
      Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in pencil. Score (27 p.); 35 cm.
      Photocopy of score. 36 cm.
      Microfilm of score, roll 1. (in Box 4)
    - [Quartet, strings, no. 2], 1939; 1 (Box 6, Folder 112-113)
      Parts. 32 cm.
    - [Symphony, string orchestra] Symphony for large string orchestra., 1940-1944 (Box 6, Folder 114)
      - Holograph signed, in ink. Score (57 p.); 34 cm. Contains some sketches in pencil for arr. for full orchestra, [1940]; 1 (Box 6, Folder 114)
      - Another version: Symphony for string orchestra., 1 (Box 6, Folder 114)
      - Holograph signed, in ink. Score ([2], 44 p.); 38 cm. Onionskin, no date; 1 (Box 6, Folder 115)
      - 3 photocopies of above. 36, 39, 39 cm. The last one contains markings in pencil, no date; 1 (Box 6, Folder 116, Box 7, Folder 117)
      - Part, violin I. 34 cm. Incomplete, pages 6-7 only, no date; 1 (Box 6, Folder 116, Box 7, Folder 117)
      - Another version: Symphony for orchestra (in memoriam Ferruccio Busoni); arr. for full orchestra., 1 (Box 6, Folder 116, Box 7, Folder 117)
      - Holograph signed, in ink. Score (78 p.); 38 cm. Onionskin, [1944?]; 1 (Box 7, Folder 118)
      - Photocopies of above. 36, 39 cm. The last one contains corrections, no date; 2 (Box 7, Folder 119)
      - Parts. flute and viola. Holographs in ink and pencil. 2, [5] p.; 34 cm. Incomplete, pages wanting? -- no date, 1 (Box 7, Folder 119)